（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）るか子よ
落ち着いて聞いてくれ
Rukako...
please calm down and listen to what I have to say.
実は お前は本当は―
You used to be a guy.
男だったのだ
This again?
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）
また そんなこと言うんですか？
（岡部）あっ 待て 泣くな！
落ち着いて最後まで聞いてくれ
Wait! Don't cry.
Just let me finish!
All of this is for Mayuri's sake.
これもすべて まゆりのため
お前には 男に
戻ってもらわなければならないんだ
I need you to go back to being a guy.
～
Fractal    Androgynous
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）あ…
ハア…
What's wrong?
（紅莉栖のせきばらい）
Your face looks like that of a man who failed at cooking instant noodles
どうしたの？
焼きそばの湯切りに失敗して―
and tossed them into the sink.
麺を全部 流し台に
ぶちまけたような顔して
I'd prefer you say that
（岡部）むしろ―
必死でためた スタンプカードを
いざ使おうとしたら―
I look like someone who tried to use all his coupons,
有効期限が切れていたときの
ような顔と言ってくれ
only to find they've all expired.
（紅莉栖）フッ
I guess you aren't so depressed that you can't joke around.
冗談で返せるくらいの
余裕はあるみたいね
Okarin, Mayushii is very disappointed in you!
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）オカリン
まゆしぃは オカリンに
ガッカリなのです
Wh-What are you talking about?
なっ 何の話だ
Don't try to fool me!
（まゆり）しらばっくれても
ダメなんだよ
You made Ruka cry, didn't you?
るかちゃん 泣かせたでしょ
（岡部）なっ なぜ それを…
H-How did you know?
When I asked her to come to the lab,
（まゆり）
一緒にラボに行こうって
誘ったら―
急に泣きだしちゃったんだから
she just started crying,
それで どうしたのって聞いたら
“お前は男だ”って言われたって
and when I asked her about it,
she said you told her she's a guy!
あっ Ｄメールのことも
聞いたのか？
You heard about the D-mail?
D-mail?
Ｄメール？
I told you not to lie to me!
ごまかそうとしても
ダメなんだからね
You should apologize to her.
オカリンは きちんと
るかちゃんに謝るべきなのです
ハア…
Okabe...
（紅莉栖）岡部…
you said something that awful to her?
そんな ひどいことを
漆原さんに？
いや待て 違うんだ
これには わけが…
Wait! That's not it!
There's a reason for it—
（紅莉栖）どんなわけだ！
I don't care.
Come with me, assistant.
助手よ 一緒に来てくれ
（紅莉栖）はあ？
（岡部）いいから！
Come on!
ああっ ちょっ ちょっと何よ！
Wh-What is it?
So the next D-mail I need to erase is the one
（岡部）…というわけで
次に取り消すべきＤメールは―
Rukako sent to her mother's pager before she was born.
るか子が生まれる前―
自分の母親の
ポケベルに送ったものだ
（紅莉栖）漆原さんが 実は男？
She was really a guy?
信じられない
I can't believe it.
But it's true.
（岡部）だが 事実だ
It was true.
事実だった
She was a guy.
（紅莉栖）彼女が男…
Was she like Hashida?
もしかして橋田(はしだ)みたいな？
えっ
（紅莉栖）あ…
（岡部･紅莉栖）これはひどい
That was mean.
No, she looked just like she does now.
（岡部）…ではなくて
見た目は あのままだ
That's okay then.
（紅莉栖）なら許す
Anyway, to save Mayuri,
とにかく まゆりを救うためには
るか子を男に戻さねばならない
I need Rukako to return to being a guy.
But you already know
だけど今回 岡部は―
what the D-mail she sent said, right?
漆原さんが送ったＤメールの内容を
知ってるわけでしょう？
Then you don't have to tell her.
だったら わざわざ
事情を話さなくても―
You could just do it yourself.
黙って取り消せば
いいんじゃないの？
I don't know the number for her mom's pager,
俺は るか子の母親の
ポケベル番号を知らないのだ
and I thought it would be better for her
それに ヘタな小細工を
弄するより―
if I told her the truth instead of lying.
真実を告げたほうが
まだ誠意はある
Your brilliant idea made her cry, didn't it?
その誠意を見せた結果
泣かせちゃったわけでしょう
That's just how you are, huh?
（るか）そんなの
いつもの設定ですよね？
It's some kind of joke, right?
冗談ですよね？
That's mean!
ひどいです 岡部さんから
そんなこと言われるなんて
I didn't think you'd say that to me.
You think that was a flag?
（紅莉栖）
…っていうか それ―
フラグが立ったんじゃない？
A flag?
フラグ？
I never said anything like,
俺は この戦いが終わったら
結婚するなどとは―
"Once this battle is over, I'm getting married."
ひと言も言っていないぞ
That's a death flag!
（紅莉栖）それは死亡フラグだ
I'm talking about a love flag.
私が言ってるのは 恋愛フラグよ
Love?
（岡部）恋愛？
Her beloved Okabe told her she's really a guy,
そう 大好きな岡部から
“お前は男だ”と言われて―
and it damaged her maiden's heart.
乙女心が ズタズタになったのよ
No way. Rukako is a guy, though.
いっ あっ いや
しかし るか子は男だぞ
That was in the previous world line, right?
（紅莉栖）
それは 前の世界線の話でしょ
（岡部）あっ
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
No Subject
Rukako
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
No Subject
Rukako
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
No Subject
Rukako
Dear Okabe,
I have something important to say.
Would you come to the shrine?
I'm waiting. I'm waiting, okay?
Rukako
No Subject
"I have something important to say..."
（岡部）〝大事な
お話があります〞
（るか）〝神社まで
来てもらえませんか？〞
Could you come to the shrine?
（岡部のせきばらい）
（るか）あっ
Okabe.
（るか）岡部さん
I'm sorry about earlier.
（岡部）
さっきは すまなかったな
No, I'm sorry for crying.
（るか）いえ 僕のほうこそ
泣きだしたりして…
So...
（岡部）それで
大事な話というのは？
what did you want to talk about?
Right. Well, I have a request.
（るか）
はい　あの 僕 お願いが…
A request?
（岡部）お願い？
I believe what you told me.
（るか）
僕 岡部さんが言ったこと信じます
それで あの…
And so, um...
（岡部）うん？
I'll become a guy again, but in exchange...
（るか）男に戻る代わりに
こっ 恋…
p-please...
恋人になってください！
be my boyfriend!
（岡部）こっ 恋人！
なぜ俺が恋人に？
B-Boyfriend?
Why would I be your boyfriend?
好きだからです
Because I love you.
おっ
Because I love you, Okabe!
（るか）岡部さんのことが
好きだからです
So, tomorrow, just for one day,
だから あした１日だけでいいので
僕と恋人になってください
won't you be my boyfriend?
N-No, but you're a gu—
（岡部）いや しかし
お前は おと…
（るか）うっ うう…
Fine...
（岡部）分かった
分かったから泣くな
I'll do it, so don't cry!
Very well.
いいだろう あした１日でいいなら
恋人になってやる
I'll be your boyfriend for a day if that's really what you want.
Really?
本当ですか？
なぜ泣く？
Why are you crying?
Because I'm so happy.
だって僕 うれしくて
（岡部）おおっ
今ちょっとキュンときた
That was actually pretty cute.
So you'll be going out with her tomorrow?
（紅莉栖）
それで あした 漆原さんと
デートすることになったのか
Yes.
はい
A mad scientist on a date with a high school girl.
（紅莉栖）狂気の
マッドサイエンティストが―
女子高生とデート
言うな
Don't say it.
That's why I'm enduring the mortification
だから こうして恥を忍び
助手風情に―
of asking a mere assistant for dating advice.
デートのしかたを
相談しているのではないか
（紅莉栖）助手じゃないって
言ってるでしょ！
I told you I'm not your assistant!
（フェイリス）ニャニャ？
You're going on a date with someone, Kyouma?
凶真(きょうま) 誰かとデートするのニャ？
Here you are!
お待たせしました
アイスコーヒーになりますニャ～
Two iced coffees.
Are you going out with Mayushii?
デートの相手は まゆしぃかニャ？
それとも…
Or with her ?
この子なのかニャ？
No, this is my assistant.
（岡部）いいや こいつは助手だ
Even if it helps you perfect your ultimate technique,
奥義習得の任務のためとはいえ―
手当たりしだいに いろんな子に
手を出しすぎだニャ フフフフ
you're chasing far too many girls.
（紅莉栖）ほ～
手当たりしだいに いろんな子に…
Too many girls, huh?
あっ お… おい
Hey! Don't say things that'll be easily misconstrued right before you leave!
誤解を生むようなことだけ
言い残して 去るな！
Hey, would you...
（紅莉栖）ねえ
岡部って その…
奥義習得のためなら
なんでもできちゃうの？
Would you do anything to perfect your ultimate technique?
はあ？
I-I mean, would Hououin Kyouma do anything?
あっ いや だからその…
設定の中での話よ！
Why are you talking about this too?
なぜ お前まで設定の話になる？
意味が分からん
I don't understand.
J-Just curious!
なっ なんとなくよ
I was just wondering if you'd do anything to perfect your ultimate technique,
愛する人がいたとしても
奥義習得のためなら―
even if you already had someone you loved...
なんでもできる設定なのかなって…
特に意味はないんだからな！
There's no real meaning behind it, okay?!
（岡部）なぜ そこで怒る
Why are you getting mad?
I'm not mad!
怒ってない！
Anyways, if that's how you're gonna act,
…っていうか
そんな設定なんだったら―
why not go on a date with her?
漆原さんと デートして
あげれば いいじゃない
I already told you that I was going to!
だから 最初から
デートすると言ってるだろう！
Okarin...
（橋田 至(いたる)）オカリーン
I'd really appreciate it if you'd fill me in on the details.
今の話 僕にも詳しく
聞かせてもらいたいわけだが
（橋田）デートのことなら
これまで何十人もの女の子と―
If you want to know where to go on a date,
I've kissed dozens of girls.
チュッチュしてきた僕に
任せるといいよ
I'll tell you everything you need to know!
There's Nene, Shiori, Honoka, Rinko...
ねねちゃん しおりちゃん
ほのかちゃん りんこちゃん
（岡部）うん それはすべて
ゲームの中の女子だろう
All those girls are from games.
I'm talking about a real date.
俺は 現実の
デートの話をしているのだ
I heard you usually go to Aoyama, Omotesandou,
デートといえば 青山(あおやま)だとか
表参道(おもてさんどう)だとか 西麻布(にしあざぶ)だとか…
or Nishiazabu.
Fashionable and trendy...
おしゃれでトレンデーな…
A premium night...
プレミアムな夜に…
A special dinner...
特別なディナー　ううっ
無理だ これは別世界だ
It's hopeless.
This is a different world...
None of it exists in reality.
現実には 存在しない世界なのだ
What do you get by denying it?
（紅莉栖）そこを否定してどうする
I, Hououin Kyouma, was born
そもそも
アイザック･ニュートンと同じく
with an IQ of 170, just like Isaac Newton.
ＩＱ170に生まれついた
この俺 鳳凰院(ほうおういん)凶真
I am a mad scientist,
興味があるのは
女よりも研究であって…
and I prefer research over girls—
Definitely a virgin!
どう見ても 童貞です
本当に ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
So what about you?
そういう お前はどうなのだ
Do you have enough dating experience
そんな偉そうな口をきけるほど
デート経験豊富なのか？
to talk down to me?
うあっ
See?
それみろ　お前だって
勉強や研究に明け暮れて―
You've been so busy with studying and research
that you've never been on a single date, right?
そういった経験はゼロなのだろう
You had a lonely youth, didn't you?
さみしい青春時代を
送ってきたのだろう
Shut up! Is it so wrong to be a virgin?!
（紅莉栖）うっさい
バージンで悪いか！
（岡部）えっ
（紅莉栖）はっ
（紅莉栖）あ…
With first dates, the most important thing
（紅莉栖）
“初デートで重要なのは―”
is making yourself presentable to your partner.
“相手に与える印象を
いかに よくするかです”
Regarding clothing,
“服装に関しては ブランド物で
きめる必要はなく―”
there's no need to wear expensive brand names,
but something clean—
“清潔感のある…”
I'm fine there.
そこはオーケーだな
There's nothing cleaner than a lab coat.
白衣ほど清潔なものはない
Who goes on a date in a lab coat?
白衣でデートはないだろう
The same applies to your destination.
“店選びに関しても同じです”
There's no need to pay for an expensive high-end restaurant.
“無理をして
高級店に入る必要はありません”
The places you normally go are fine.
“ふだんの自分の行きつけの店で
十分です”
行きつけ… ここはないな
Places I'd normally...
Guess here won't work.
Of course not.
当たり前でしょ
この殺伐とした店内で―
You can't take her somewhere gloomy like this!
どんなデートするつもりよ
I suppose the other place I frequent would be...
ほかに行きつけといえば―
May Queen.
「メイクイーン」？
はあ？ 初デートでメイドカフェ？
A maid café for a first date?
The weapons store.
「武器屋本舗」
Why are you buying a weapon?
（紅莉栖）武器を買ってどうする
えーい
You're just reading from a dating book,
デートマニュアルを
音読してるだけの分際で―
so stop shooting everything down,
その上から目線は やめろ
このメリケン処女めが
you American virgin.
Who's an American virgin?
（紅莉栖）誰がメリケン処女だ！
Who else but you?!
（岡部）お前以外に誰がいる？
Yeah, yeah. You're a virgin too.
（紅莉栖）はいはい 童貞乙(おつ)
Hey, wouldn't this be a better book to read?
（橋田）…っつーか
そんな本より やっぱこっちじゃね
That's a dating sim walkthrough!
それはエロゲの攻略本だろ？
（橋田）いいじゃん！
Who cares?!
デートっていえば
エロイベントだろ
Erotic things happen on dates all the time,
like holding hands and stuff. That's erotic!
手をつなぐとか マジエロくね？
Or when she takes your arms and presses her breasts against you,
腕組んで おっぱい
ひじに当ててんのよ状態とか
that's erotic as fuck!
エロ過ぎっしょ
And at the end of the date, there's a kiss.
そして デートの終わりには
キスして締めだろ チクショウ！
Damn it all!
Screw all you normalfags!
リア充のバカー！
（岡部）結局
何のプランも立たぬまま 朝か
So it's morning, and I have no plan.
（紅莉栖）ふん
ブツブツ言ってないで
とっとと着替える
Stop complaining and get dressed!
Take off the tags.
タグちゃんと外して
Who ties their tie like that? I can't believe you.
何 そのネクタイの締め方
信じらんない
You're a mess, you know that?
まったく 世話が焼けるわね
はい
Here.
（岡部）なんだか
首輪を付けられた気分だ
I feel like someone just put a chain around my neck.
Here's a handkerchief too.
はい ハンカチも
You know how to use that, right?
どうやって使うか 分かってる？
"I'm still waiting for you."
今でも あなたのことを
待っています という合図
That's for the yellow handkerchief of happiness.
（紅莉栖）
それは幸せの黄色いやつ
その偏った知識はなんだ？
おまけに古い
Where did you learn these things?
That's old, anyway.
Yet you knew it.
お前も知ってるではないか
（紅莉栖）あっ うっ 悪い？
Well, my bad.
The correct answer is,
正解は 女の子が
公園のベンチに座るときに広げる
"You spread it out before she sits on a bench."
まあ いいわ
こっそりあとをつけて
Well, whatever.
I'll tail you and text you advice.
いざってときは メールで
アドバイスしてあげるから
You're coming with me?
なっ ついてくるのか？
So is Hashida.
（紅莉栖）橋田も一緒にね
へっ？
Operation Valkyria begins!
（紅莉栖）オペレーション
ヴァルキリア 開始よ！
Why Norse mythology?
（岡部）なぜ 北欧神話なのだ
It's critical that you're not late.
（岡部）待ち合わせにおいては
遅刻は厳禁
Be 15 minutes early at the very least.
遅くとも 15分前には
着いておくこと
はっ あっ
岡部さーん
Okabe!
おっ おお
（るか）すみません
I'm sorry!
（岡部）おお
I thought I left early too.
（るか）早めに
出たつもりだったんですけど―
Were you waiting long?
お待たせしちゃいましたか？
おお いや
俺も 今来たところだ
No... I just got here.
ハア よかった
Oh, good...
（岡部）あっ
Th-Then shall we go?
で… では行くか
Yes!
（るか）はい
（橋田）うっ
I've never seen you without a lab coat on.
（るか）白衣じゃない岡部さん
初めて見ました
（岡部）
ま… まあ デートだからな
Th-This is a date, after all.
はっ
When you're walking with a girl,
（岡部）女の子と歩くときは
自分は さりげなく車道側を歩く
you should subtly take the side with oncoming traffic.
どうかしましたか？
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
（岡部）あっ いや なんでもない
おっと なんだあれは！
What's that?!
That wasn't subtle at all!
ちっとも さりげなくない
When a bike or car approaches, subtly protect her.
（岡部）そして 車やバイクと
すれ違うとき
さりげなく 女の子をガード
はっ おっと
ガードした？
Did he protect her?
（るか）岡部さん？
Okabe!
（岡部）あたたた…
Are you okay?
（メイド）大丈夫ですか？
…と思ったら 転んだだけ？
No, he just tripped,
and then a maid helped him up and gave him tissues?
しかも そこで
メイドさんに助けられ―
ティッシュまでもらって どうする
What on Earth...
Miss Makise, you seem upset.
（橋田）牧瀬氏
なんかイライラしてる？
I-It's nice out today, isn't it?
きょ 今日は いい天気ですね
Yeah.
ああ
But there are some clouds.
だが 少し雲はあるな
Yeah...
（るか）そうですね
This cake's very good.
（るか）
このケーキ とってもおいしいです
（岡部）うん コーヒーもうまい
The coffee is too.
（岡部）なぜだ なぜ今まで
普通に話せていたのに
Why?
I've spoken normally with her my whole life,
デートと意識したとたん…
but the moment we're on a date...
（るか）ここ ステキなお店ですね
This is a wonderful restaurant.
よく来るんですか？
Do you come here often?
No.
（岡部）いや
（岡部）このままでは マズい
This is bad.
A smooth flowing conversation is imperative.
重要なのは
会話のキャッチボールだ
Th-This is actually my first time here.
じっ 実は今日が初めてなのだが…
投げ返した
He actually answered her question?
Today, August 14th, is Patent Day
（岡部）初めてといえば
今日８月14日は―
to celebrate when the first patent was issued in Japan.
日本で初めて 専売特許が
交付された 特許記念日だ
どこに投げてんのよ
What kind of conversation is that?
（るか）岡部さんって
いろんなこと知ってるんですね
You sure know a lot, Okabe.
えっ まあな
I-I guess.
（橋田）牧瀬氏 もう帰らん？
Wanna go home, Miss Makise?
We're just watching. We can't help at all.
僕たちは見てるだけで
何の役にも立ってないし
No, we must see this to the end.
いえ 最後まで見届けるのよ
Thank you.
（店員）ありがとうございました
フウ
Um...
（るか）あの
（岡部）おっ
Is it boring?
やっぱり つまらないでしょうか？
僕なんかとデートしても
Going on a date with me, that is.
おっ バカ 何を言う
What are you talking about?!
Next, we'll walk around town.
次は街をブラブラするぞ
ついてこい
Come with me!
（まゆり）うん？
Ruka?
るかちゃん？
So hot...
（橋田）あっちいー
（紅莉栖）うう
He's just walking the whole way to Ueno and back?
ひたすら歩いて
上野まで往復って…
（るか）岡部さん
（岡部）おっ
Okabe...
do you remember the first time we met?
初めて会ったときのこと
覚えてますか？
Yeah...
うん？
You saved me after some men with cameras accosted me.
カメラを持った男の人たちに
絡まれて 困ってたところを―
助けてくれたんですよね
ああ… ああ
Yeah.
あっ ありがとうございました
Thank you!
But I'm really sorry.
でも すみません
うん？ なぜ謝る
Why are you apologizing?
だって僕は
こんな顔なのに 男だから
Because...
I look this way, but I'm a guy!
Who cares if you're a girl or a guy?
（岡部）お前が男だろうが
女だろうが 関係ない
ハッ
That doesn't matter at all!
そんなことは どうでもいい
Back then,
（るか）あのとき 岡部さんが
言ってくれた言葉が―
what you said made me so happy.
すごく うれしかったんです
It was those words that made me start to like you.
あの言葉があったから
岡部さんのこと好きになったんです
"That doesn't matter at all," huh?
“そんなことは どうでもいい”か
あっ いや ちょっと待て
Wait! Aren't those memories from when you were a guy?
それは るか子が男だったときの
記憶ではないのか？
えっ あれ？
I... What am I saying?
僕… 僕 何を言ってるんだろう
なんだか混乱して
I feel kind of strange...
It's just like it was with Feyris.
（岡部）
フェイリスのときと同じだ
She's remembering the last world line.
前の世界線の記憶が…
Thank you for today.
（るか）今日は
ありがとうございました
恋人になってくださって
すごく…
I'm so happy... so happy...
so happy you were my boyfriend for today.
すごく 幸せでした
おい
Hey...
This is the number for my mom's pager.
（るか）これ お母さんの
ポケベルの番号です
うっ
"Meat, meat, vegetables, vegetables, meat, meat, vegetables, vegetables."
（紅莉栖）肉肉 野菜野菜―
肉肉 野菜野菜
If she sees this, I'm sure Urushibara's mom
これを見れば 漆原さんの
お母さんも きっと―
will assume the last one was a prank.
前のメッセージは
いたずらだったと思うはず
We're ready!
準備できたわよ
（岡部）ハア
What's wrong, Okabe?
どうしたの 岡部
（まゆり）トゥットゥルー
Hey, hey...
あのね あのね
まゆしぃ さっき―
Mayushii saw Ruka on a date with someone!
るかちゃんが 誰かと
デートしてるのを見ちゃったのです
That was Okarin.
ああ それ オカリンだよ
No way.
（まゆり）えー ウソだ
あんなの絶対 オカリンじゃないよ
It definitely wasn't Okarin...
He was wearing normal clothes,
だって なんか普通の服着てたし
結構 紳士っぽかったし…
and he looked like a gentleman—
She's right.
（岡部）そのとおりだ
あんなのは俺じゃない
It wasn't me.
That wasn't a date with the real me!
あれじゃ るか子は
俺とデートしたとは言えない
Okarin?
オカリン？
（岡部）ハア ハア…
まだデートは終わってない
The date isn't over!
（るか）えっ でも岡部さん
But Okabe...
Kyouma!
凶真だ 我が名を忘れたか るか子
Have you forgotten my name, Rukako?
Guys, girls, boyfriends...
男だとか 女だとか 恋人だとか
混乱していたのは 俺のほうだった
I was the one who was confused.
None of that matters!
そんなことは どうでもいい
I finally realized...
俺は ようやく気付いた
俺は俺であり るか子はるか子
I am me, and you are Rukako, my protégé!
俺の弟子だ
あっ…
Right!
はい
So bring me the dark blade, Summer Rain!
分かったら
妖刀五月雨(さみだれ)を持ってこい
（るか）えい！
（岡部）そうだ！
That's right!
（るか）やあ！
（岡部）その調子だ！
That's exactly right!
（るか）はい
Yes!
えいっ
Listen, Rukako.
（岡部）いいか るか子 よく聞け
Listen well.
The legend of this dark blade goes back
そもそも この妖刀に
まつわる伝説は―
to the age of Yoshitsune.
義経(よしつね)の時代にさかのぼる
On the night of the full blood-red moon,
死の色をした満月の夜
道に迷った１人の野武士が…
a traveler was lost on the roads.
やっちまったな オカリン
Look at him go.
Good.
よかったー
るかちゃんと仲直りしたんだ
He made up with Ruka.
I guess he doesn't need us anymore.
（紅莉栖）私たちはもう
必要ないみたいね
Please save Mayuri.
（るか）まゆりちゃんのこと
助けてあげてください
（岡部）えっ
（るか）岡部さんの探している
古いパソコン
The old PC you're looking for...
The IBN 5100?
（岡部）ＩＢＮ5100か
Until last New Year's, it was in our storehouse,
（るか）確かに去年のお正月まで
うちの倉庫にありました
（岡部）なっ
（るか）でも―
but I broke it while I was cleaning the storehouse,
僕が壊しちゃったんです
倉庫の掃除をしていたときに
so it's all my fault!
だから 僕のせいなんです
岡部さん お願いします
Okabe, please...
save Mayuri!
まゆりちゃんを
助けてあげてください
I was so happy to have the chance to train with you.
久しぶりに
岡部さんと修行ができて―
本当によかったです
Ruka—
（岡部）るか…
（るか）もう行ってください
Please go.
If you don't, I think I'm going to cry...
じゃないと僕
泣いちゃいそうで
I should say the words, shouldn't I?
こういうときは
例の合言葉ですよね
El Psy Congray.
エル･プサイ･コンガリィ
（岡部）コングルゥだ
Congroo.
El Psy...
エル プサイ…
I really don't want to go back...
（るか）僕…
本当は戻りたくないです
だって だって―
Because... Because...
男に戻ったら
岡部さんへの この気持ち―
If I go back,
I'll have to hide the feelings I have for you!
封印しなくちゃいけないから
I don't think I'll be able to love you if I'm a guy...
男なのに
岡部さんのこと好きでいちゃ―
いけないと思うから
Rukako...
（岡部）るか子
男に戻ったら―
If I go back to being a guy,
I'm going to forget all about today.
今日のことも全部
忘れちゃうんですよね？
デートしたことも
久しぶりに２人で修行したことも
That we went on a date...
That the two of us trained...
こうして 岡部さんの
体に触れていることも
That I was able to hold you like this.
こんなに つらい気持ちを
味わうんなら―
If I had to suffer like this,
I should've never wished to be a girl!
女の子になりたいなんて
願うんじゃなかった！
Even if you go back to being a guy,
（岡部）お前が男に戻っても
俺にとって るか子はるか子だ
you'll still be Rukako to me.
何も変わらない
Nothing will change!
そうですよね 男とか女とか―
That's right.
It doesn't matter if I'm a girl or a guy, does it?
“そんなことは どうでもいい”
ですよね
But just for a little while,
でも 少しでいいから
覚えていてください
please remember me
as a girl...
女の子だった 僕のことを
（岡部）ああ 忘れない 絶対に
I'll never forget.
うっ　ああっ
（るか）
どうしたんですか？ 岡部さん
What's wrong, Okabe?
（岡部）おお…
Urushibara Ruka,
（岡部）漆原るか
声もしぐさも女にしか見えない
the mannerisms and voice of a woman...
No, more feminine than any woman.
いや 女よりも女らしい美少女
Hey, Rukako...
なあ るか子
（るか）はい
Yes?
Do you like me?
（岡部）お前は 俺のこと好きか？
Wh-What are you saying?
えっ いきなり何を
好きか？
Do you?
えーっと その 尊敬してます
Um... Well, I respect you!
But... he's a guy.
（岡部）だが 男だ
Just one message left.
（岡部）残るメールは…
あと１つ
～